<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Feylost</name>
		<description>Feylost Background</description>
		<author url="https://dnd.wizards.com/products/wild-beyond-witchlight">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.5">
			<file name="background-feylost.xml" url="https://github.com/Monshroom/Aurorathewildbeyondthewitchlight/blob/main/user/TheWildBeyondTheWitchlight/background-feylost.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Feylost" type="Background" source="The Wild Beyond The Witchlight" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEYLOST">
			<description>
			<p>You grew up in the Feywild after dissapearing from your home plane as a child. Perhaps you were spirited away by a kindly Fey who thought you were destined for great things.
				Perhaps you stumbled through a fey crossing by chance during a twilight stroll in the woods. Perhaps you were kidnapped by evil Fey but sscaped from their clutches. 
				Whatever the manner of your disappearance, you gradually fell under the Feywild's spell and learned a little about the nature of the mercurial tricksters that dwell there.
				When you finally returned to your home plane, you dit not come back unchanged. 
				You are haunted by the fact that the Feywild —a mirror world hidden behind a mere twist of perception— is only a a hair's breadth away. Although your memories of the Feywild grow fainter with each passing day,
				your heart swells with a mixture of fear and joy at the prospect of one day venturing back into the Plane of Faerie —your home awa from home</p>

			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong>Deception, Survival</li>
				<li><strong>Languages:</strong>One of your choice of Elvish, Gnomish, Goblin, or Sylvan.</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong>A musical instrument (one of your choice), a set of traveler's clothes, three trinkets (each determinded by rolling on the Feywild Trinkets Table), and a pouch containing 8 gp</li>
			</ul>
			</description>
			<h5>Fey Mark</h5>
			<p>You were transformed in some small way by your stay in the Feywild and gained a fey mark, determinded by rolling on the Fey Mark table. </p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-20">d8</td><td>Fey Mark</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Your eyes swirl with iridecent colors.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>You have a sweet scent, like that of nectar or honey.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>You have long whiskers like those of a cat.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Your ears are covered with soft tufts of fur.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Your skin sparkles in the moonlight.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Flowers either bloom or wilt (your choiche) in your presence.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7</td><td>Your hair is made of vines or brambles and grows back to normal length within 1 hour of being cut.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>You have a tail like that of a dog or another animal.</td></tr>
			</table>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">Deception, Survival</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" />
			<select name="Fey Mark" type="List" optional="true">
				<item id="1">Your eyes swirl with iridecent colors.</item>
				<item id="2">You have a sweet scent, like that of nectar or honey.</item>
				<item id="3">You have long whiskers like those of a cat.</item>
				<item id="4">Your ears are covered with soft tufts of fur.</item>
				<item id="5">Your skin sparkles in the moonlight.</item>
				<item id="6">Flowers either bloom or wilt (your choiche) in your presence.</item>
				<item id="7">Your hair is made of vines or brambles and grows back to normal length within 1 hour of being cut.</item>
				<item id="8">You have a tail like that of a dog or another animal.</item>
				</select>
				</rules>
			<select name="Personality Trait" type="List" number="2">
				<item id="1">I'm haunted by fey laughter that only I can hear, though I know it's just my mind playing tricks on me.</item>
				<item id="2">Like a nomad, I can't settle down in one place for very long.</item>
				<item id="3">Good music makes me weep like a baby.</item>
				<item id="4">Wherever I go, I try to bring a little warmth and tranquilty of home with me.</item>
				<item id="5">I have never lost my childlike sense of wonder.</item>
				<item id="6">When I have a new idea, I get wildly excitedabout it until I come up with another, better idea.</item>
				<item id="7">I live by my own set of weird and wonderful rules.</item>
				<item id="8">I can't bring myself to trust most adults.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Ideal" type="List">
				<item id="1">Friendship. I never leave a friend behind. (Good)</item>
				<item id="2">Empathy. No creature should be made to suffer. (Good)</item>
				<item id="3">Wanderlust. I prefer to take the less traveled path. (Chaotic)</item>
				<item id="4">Changeability. Change is good, which is why I live by an everchanging set of rules. (Chaotic)</item>
				<item id="5">Honor. A deal is a deal, and I would never break one. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="6">Rule of Three. Everything in the multiverse happens in threes. I see the "rule of three" everywhere. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="7">Obsession. I won't let go of a grudge. (Evil)</item>
				<item id="8">Greed. I will do whatever it takes to get what I want, regardless of the harm it might cause. (Evil)</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Bond" type="List">
				<item id="1">I would never break my word</item>
				<item id="2">I find magic in all its forms to be compelling. The more magical a place, the more I'm drawn to it.</item>
				<item id="3">I do what I can to protect the natural world.</item>
				<item id="4">A trusted friend is the most important thing in the multivers to me.</item>
				<item id="5">I can't bring myself to harm a Fey creature, either because I consider myself one or because I fear the repercussions.</item>
				<item id="6">The Witchlight Carnival feels like home to me.</item>
				<item id="7">I'm drawn to the Feywild and long to return there, if only for a short time.</item>
				<item id="8">I feel indebted to Mister Witch and Mister Light for giving me a home and a purpose.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Flaw" type="List">
				<item id="1">I lose track of time. My poor sense of time means I am always late.</item>
				<item id="2">I think the whole multiverse is out to get me.</item>
				<item id="3">I'm always operating under a thight timelinem and I'm obsessed with keeping everything on schedule.</item>
				<item id="4">I'm a kleptomaniac who covets shiny, sparkling, treasure.</item>
				<item id="5">I'm forgetful. Sometimes I can't remember even the simpelest things.</item>
				<item id="6">I never give away anything for free and always expect something in return.</item>
				<item id="7">I have many vices and tend to indulge them.</item>
				<item id="8">I'm always changing my mind —well, almost always.</item>
			</select>
		
	</element>
	
</elements>